<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>udacity on Blog - Nitish Puri</title>
    <link>https://www.myproductionurl.com/tags/udacity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in udacity on Blog - Nitish Puri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.myproductionurl.com/tags/udacity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Robotics Engineer Nanodegree :: Term 2</title>
      <link>https://www.myproductionurl.com/research/robotics/rsend-term2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.myproductionurl.com/research/robotics/rsend-term2/</guid>
      <description>Starting the term 2 of Udacity Robotics Software Engineer Nanodegree today. Will be updating this page with micro breifs of topics and projects for the term.
This term focuses on localisation and mapping problems based on probabilistic and deep reinforcement learning models deployed on embedded hardware(NVIDIA Jetson Tx2).
High Level Topics  Probabilistic Robotics. Introduction to Jetson Robotic System Deployment. Localization. Mapping and SLAM RL Basics Path Planning and RL Navigation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inverse Kinematics on Kuka Arm using ROS and Python</title>
      <link>https://www.myproductionurl.com/research/robotics/kuka-kinematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.myproductionurl.com/research/robotics/kuka-kinematics/</guid>
      <description>Picking and placing objects is something that we as humans take for granted. That&amp;rsquo;s not the case for our mechanical(and electronic) friends. They have to
 Calculate an optimal collision-free path from the source to target location. Perform inverse kinematics to control the joints on your arm. Pick the object cleanly,without knocking over other objects in your path(well, this one doesn&amp;rsquo;t always go very well for us either).  One of the most challenging projects that I did in my Udacity Robotics Nanodegree program was to control a 6-jointed robot arm to pick and place an object.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
